Finding Aid for the Fletcher Bascom Dresslar Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Fletcher B. Dresslar Papers
1888-1930
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0120
4.62 linear_feet
Biography
Sept. 28, 1858 Born, Banta, Indiana
1889 A.B., Indiana University
1892 A.M., Indiana University
1894 Ph.D., Clark University, Worcester, Massachusetts Universities of Berlin and Munich Research at British Museum
1894 - 1897 Professor of Psychology and Education, State Normal School, Los Angeles, California
1897 - 1909 Professor of Science and the Art of Teaching, University of California
1909 - 1911 Professor of Education and Dean of School of Education, University of Alabama
1911 Editor, Office of Education
1911 - 1912 Specialist in School Hygiene and Sanitation, Office of Education
1912 - 1930 Special Agent in Schoolhouse Construction, Office of Education Professor of School Hygiene, Peabody College for Teachers, Nashville, Tennessee
1919 Survey of Julius Rosenwald Schools in the South
March 3, 1922 Married Minnie Fisher, Nashville, Tennessee
1928 Organized Interstate School Building Service
Jan. 19, 1930 Died, Nashville, Tennessee
Jan. 26, 1951 Minnie Fisher Dresslar died, Nashville, Tennessee
Sons: Otis Dresslar Oscar Dresslar
Honorary Life Member of the National Council of Schoolhouse Construction President, Tennessee Academy of Science
- Outgoing Correspondence
  - Nov. 25, 1911 - Dec. 31, 1912, undated, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jan. 1. 1913 - Jan. 13, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jan. 14, 1913 - Jan. 18, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jan. 21, 1913 - Jan. 25, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jan. 27, 1913 - Jan. 31, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Feb. 1, 1913 - Feb. 6, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Feb. 7, 1913 - Feb. 27, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - March 1, 1913 - March 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - March 10, 1913 - March 14, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - March 15, 1913 - March 25, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - March 27, 1913 - April 2, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - April 3, 1913 - April 12, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April 14, 1913 - April 24, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - April 25, 1913 - April 30, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - May 1, 1913 - June 2, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - June 3, 1913 - June 9, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - June 10, 1913 - June 17, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - June 21, 1913 - Sept. 13, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sept. 15, 1913 - Oct. 30, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nov. 1, 1913 - Nov. 11, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Nov. 12, 1913 - Nov. 21, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Nov. 24, 1913 - Dec. 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dec. 2, 1913 - Dec. 12, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dec. 13, 1913 - Dec. 24, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Jan. 9, 1914 - Jan. 24, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Feb. 4, 1914 - Feb. 20, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Feb. 21, 1914 - April 30, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - May 15, 1914 - Aug. 27, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sept. 2, 1914 - Nov. 24, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dec. 1, 1914 - Dec. 31, 1914, undated, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jan. 5, 1915 - Feb. 19, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Feb. 20, 1915 - March 3, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - March 4, 1915 - March 7, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - March 8, 1915 - March 15, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - March 16, 1915 - April 10, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - April 13, 1915 - May 4, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - May 5, 1915 - June 15, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - June 21, 1915 - July 31, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Oct. 13, 1915 - Dec. 27, 1915, undated, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Jan. 6, 1916 - March 24, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - March 27, 1916 - April 29, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - May 3, 1916 - Aug. 26, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Aug. 28, 1916 - Dec. 29, 1916, undated, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Jan. 1, 1917 - Dec. 21, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Jan. 7, 1918 - March 28, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - April 4, 1918 - Dec. 13, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jan. 16, 1919 - June 16, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - June 18, 1919 - Dec. 23, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jan. 5, 1920 - Dec. 12, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jan. 8, 1921 - Dec. 27, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jan. 19, 1922 - Dec. 14, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Jan. 5, 1923 - Dec. 13, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Jan. 19, 1924 - Dec. 29, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jan. 2, 1925 - Dec. 23, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jan. 5, 1926 - Dec. 30, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Jan. 3, 1927 - Jan. 29, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Feb. 7, 1927 - April 30, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - May 2, 1927 - June 28, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - July 1, 1927 - Oct. 17, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Oct. 27, 1927 - Dec. 30, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Jan. 3, 1928 - July 28, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Aug. 2, 1928 - Dec. 31, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jan. 5, 1929 - April 30, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - May 1, 1929 - Sept. 17, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Sept. 19, 1929 - Dec. 31, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fragments (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Abbott - Affleck (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Albright - American Seating Co. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ames - Aspinwall (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Astrin - Ayres (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Babbitt - Bancroft, G. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bancroft, J. - Baruch (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bawden, W. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Beagle - Benner (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bennet - Bischoff (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bishop - Boyden (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Boykin, J. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bracken - Brewster, M. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Brewster, W. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Briere - Brown (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Browne - Bugg (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Buice - Byrne (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cady - Carmichael (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Carpenter - Caudill (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Challman, S. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chamberlain - Cherry (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Childs - Claxton (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Claxton, P. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Claxton, P. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Claxton, P. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Claxton, P. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Claxton - Clow (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cobb - Cook (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cooper - Corwin (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cotting - Crosier (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cross - Curtis (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dadisman - Dennis (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Denton - Dodge (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Dodson - Doten (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Dougherty - Dry (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Duffey - Dunn (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Earl - Edwards (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Eells - Ellis (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Elmore - Evans (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Everett - Exner (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Falk - Feagin (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fee - Firth (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Fisher - Fones (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ford - Foster (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Fraley - Fulton (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Galloway - Goin (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Goldan - Goldsberry (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Goldy - Greeley (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Green - Griffith (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Griggs - Guss (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hacker - Hargraves (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Harman - Hartwell (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Haskins - Haynes (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Heald - Henry, J.E. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Henry, J.H. - Hirst (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hoagland - Holt (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Honoour - Howell (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Howey - Hutchinson (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Imhof - Ittner (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ittner - Ivy (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jackson - Johnson, J. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Johnson, L. - Judd (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kaine - Kalbach (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Kalbach, L. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Kalbach, L. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Kanter - Kilham (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - King - Kingsley, S. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Kingsley, S. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Kingsley - Kupfer (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - L. Wolff Mfg. Co. - Lee (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - LeGarde - Logan (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lombardi - Lyne (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - McAfee - McClain, E. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - McClain, E. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - McClain, E. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - McClain, E. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - McClellan - McCuistion (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - McCulley - Mcilhenny (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mcintire - McTate (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Macmillan - Martien (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Martin - Miller (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Milligan - Moore, J. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Moore, M. - Morrison (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Morrow - Myrick (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Naramore - Netcott (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Newhouse - Nutter (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Oberteuffer - Owen (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Packard - Payne (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Pearse - Platt (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Pleasant - Pruett (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pruett - Py (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Ragan - Ray (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Reams - Rittenhouse (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Roach - Roberts (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Robertson - Rogers (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Rohan - Rupert (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Russell - Ryan (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Salmon - Sears (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Seaver - Shaw (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Shawkey - Small, W. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Small, W. - Smith, J.F. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Smith, J.L. - Stechert (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Steele - Storey (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Storey - Sydenham (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Talbott - Taylor, H.L. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Taylor, H.L. - Thompson (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Thouet Brothers - Towner (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Townsend - Twiss (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Underwood - Virtue and Co. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Waddell - Wardlaw (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Washburn - Whaley (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Wheeler - Windes (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Wirth - Wood (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Wood, T. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Wood, T. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Wood, T. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Wood - Wynn (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Yakel - Zook (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Fragments (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified (Box 9, Folder 12)
- WRITINGS
  - "Activities ...." - Central (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Child ...." - "Community ...." (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "The Construction ...." - "The Educational. ..." (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Fire" - "Growth .... " (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Health ...." - "High .... " (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "How ...." - "Lighting .... (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Location ...." - "New .... " (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "A New ...." - Principals (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Psychology ...." - "The School. ... " (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - School Building - "Suggestions .... " (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Supervision ...." - "Two .... " (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "The Tyranny ...." - Work Space (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fragments (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fragments (Box 10, Folder 1)
- PERSONAL / PHOTOGRAPHS / NOTES / MISCELLANEOUS / PUBLICATIONS / WRITINGS BY OTHERS
  - Personal
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Dec. 30, 1914 - Dec. 7, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Membership Cards (Box 11)
    - Certificate (Box 11)
    - Hillsboro Church, Nashville, Jan. 26, 1930, Bulletin (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Kappa Delta Pi, July 12, 1928, Membership Card (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - National Council of Schoolhouse Construction, Oct. 23-25, 1929, Bulletin (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - National Education Association, undated, Membership Card (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - New York Academy of Medicine, April 20, 1915, Invitation (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Report of Work Done for Month Ending, Jan. 31, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Report of Work Done for Month Ending, Feb. 28, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Report of Work Done for Month Ending, March 31, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Report of Work Done for Month Ending, April 30, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Royalty Statement, July 1, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Southern Sociological Congress, Aug. 11, 1915-March 30, 1916 Certificates of Delegation (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Theta Chapter of Phi Gamma Delta, Feb. 21, 1914, Invitation (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - NOTES
    - "Am I My Brother's Keeper: ...", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Aphasia, April 12, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Building Recommendations, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Care and Culture", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Comments on the Plans of the Hume-Fogg High School of Nashville, Tennessee", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - County Health Statistics, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "General Principles", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "The Growth of the Dignity of Motherhood", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Health Education in George Peabody College for Teachers", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Hygiene, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Invest in Yourselves .... " (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Joke, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Marshall's Pencils", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Mathematical Problems, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Needs of Schools, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "A New Patriotism", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "On Boarding Schools and Consumption and Primary School", 1907-1913 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Physical Education, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Play, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Porter School, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Poem, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Possible Experiments", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Relation of Character to Good Health", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Religion", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Resident Physician, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Rural Sanitation, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Sex Education, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "The Study of Adolescence", 1891 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Suggestions from the Psychology of Adolescence", undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Suggestions on Sketch Enclosed", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Theory and Practice", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "To define means to limit....", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified outline, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Public Health Service, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Ventilation", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Vision", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Walls, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "We cannot read far in the history of....", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "What the Appalachian Training School Has", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Why I Plant a Garden", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Notebooks (2), undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Fragments (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Bibliographies, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Central Church of Christ, Thoughts, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Code for Plans of Rural School Buildings", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Diseases Dangerous to Public Health in the Virgin Islands of the United States", March 11, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Georgia State Board of Health", Jan. 31, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "How to Prevent Worry", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Investigations Made in Department of Health Education", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Kirkwood Hall, photograph, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "List Board of Health Literature Requested of", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - McClelland Public Library, Pueblo, Colorado, photograph, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Mailing Lists (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Map, United States (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Map, YMCA Location (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Scholarship Information (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Medical Inspection of Schools (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Council of Education Program, March 1, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Council of Schoolhouse Construction, Program, Nov. 18-29, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Outline to Scientific Study of Blackboards, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Health Exposition Program, Feb. 1-9, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Physical Education Bill, March 26, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Outline of the Hot Springs Summer School for Teachers, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Pear Trees, photograph, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - School Architects, Sept. 8, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Sex Education Conference, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "To What Extent are the School Administrators of S. Carolina Conserving and Improving the Health of the Public School Children of the State", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Trabajos de Higiene Escolar der Dr. Manuel Uribe Y Troncoso, public ados on Los 'An ales de Higiene Escolar,'", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - United States Civil Service Examination, Nov. 20, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Womanhood and Its Development by Dr. Luella Z. Rummel," undated, outline (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - World-Wide Fasting Movement, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Publications
    - A Calaveras Evening, with Mark Twain and Bret Harte, A Diversion for the English Class, introduction by Edward Hyatt (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - North Dakota State Board of Health BuJletin, July 1918, vol. II, no. 3 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - The Peabody Reflector and Alumni News, April 1920, vol. III, no. 4 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Physical Equipment for the School Library, Library Commission, Raleigh, North Carolina, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Report of the Committee on Physical Education and Hygiene, California Council of Education, March, 1898 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Reports ofDepartment Committees, American Unitarian Association, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Sierra Educational News and Book Review, California Council of Education, May, 1911, vol. VII, no. 5 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Willys Knight, Willys-Overland, Inc., 1927 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Others
    - Ashley, George H. - Galloway, T.W. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Hogan, W.E. - North Carolina State Board of Health (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Priestly, H.J. - Wood, Thomas D., unidentified (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Publications
  - The Auxiliary Schools of Germany, 1907
  - Superstition, and Education, 1907
  - American Schoolhouses, 1911
  - School Hygiene, 1913
  - Ethics of Trees, 1921
  - Open Air Schools
  - Rural Schoolhouses and Grounds
  - Bulletins on school architecture and hygiene for the U.S. Office of Education
- Publication Titles
  - Activities of the Bureau of Inform..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Am I My Brother's Keeper: ......., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Holograph Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - An Appeal for Better Instruction o..., by Priestly, H.J. (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - An Investigation of the Hygienic L..., by Laird, P.E. (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Aphasia..., by Unidentified (Holograph Manuscript), 1893 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Assembly Rooms..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Basements of School Buildings..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 copies, one marked (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Blackboards..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Blood Pressure Menace, The..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), 1920; Marked (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Building Against Storms..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 copies, one marked (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Calaveras Evening with Mark Tw..., by Twain, Mark and H (Publication), undated; Introduction by Edward Hyatt (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Care and Culture..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Holograph Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Care and Culture of Our Young Peo..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; Marked (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Central Church of Christ..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), 1929; Sunday School Lecture (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Child Study..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; Marked (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Child's Right to Health, The..., by Eliz. McCormick (Publication), 1918 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Chinese Pedagogics in Practice..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Code Plans for Rural School Buil..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Colleges and Sex Education, The..., by Galloway, T.W. (Publication), 1926 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Comments..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments of the Plans of the Hu..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Holograph Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Comments on Cleveland Gramm..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on Clinton, Missouri P..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on Cordaville School..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Carter H. Harri..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 copies, one marked (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Dodge, Nebras..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Emporia High..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Guilbert Knapp..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the High School B..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 copies (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Nicholas Senn..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 copies (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Ottawa, Kansa..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Plan for the H...., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 copies (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Plan for the Hi..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Plans for the B..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Plans for the M..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Comments on the Webb City Pia..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Community Standards Recomme..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Construction and Care of School Bu..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Consumption and Primary School..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Holograph Manuscript), 1913 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Continuation Schools..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Country School Houses..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Country Schools and Country Life..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; Marked (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Cultural Value in Domestic Scien..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Department of Health Education..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Developing a Health Program in t..., by Connelly, Kather (Publication), undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Diseases Dangerous to Public He..., by Department of H (Typed Manuscript), 1927 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Drinking Fountains..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Duties and Opportunities of the Mo..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Duty of the State in the Medical I..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Educational Leaders of the Middl..., by Hogan, W.E. (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Educational Value of Music, The..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 2 marked copies (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Ethics of the Dust, The..., by Jordan, David St (Publication), 1888 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Experimental Studies in Mental D..., by Kuhlman, F. (Publication), 1904 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Fire..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Fire Protection..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Floors..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; Marked (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - General Conclusions on the Hygi..., by Dresslar, Fletcher (Typed Manuscript), undated; 4 copies (Box 9, Folder 16)